

## **ABOUT**

Hello! I am Abdullah Berkay Bayındır. I am a sophomore undergraduate Electrical and Electronics Engineer Student with strong interest in RF and embedded systems.

I am currently pursuing an Electrical and Electronics Engineering degree in Turkey also searching for professional experience. Excellent time management abilities, strong communication skills and superb problem solving skills.

## COMMUNICATION

#### E-MAIL:

bayindirberkay@gmail.com

#### LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/abdullahberkaybayindir

#### **GITHUB:**

github.com/bkbyndr

#### **INSTAGRAM:**

instagram.com/unclebk\_/

## **HOBBYS AND INTERESTS**

Amateur Astronomy Learning About Old Turkic History Playing and Watching Basketball Travelling

## **LANGUAGES**

#### English

Professional Proficiency

#### German

Intermediate Proficiency

## Turkish

Native Proficiency

# ABDULLAH BERKAY BAYINDIR

# **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

# TOBB Economy and Technology University, Ankara Turkey 2019 – Ongoing

**Faculty of Engineering** 

**Courses Taken:** Logical Čircuit Design (Verilog), Communication Systems, Computer Programming (C, C++), Probablity Theory for Electrical Engineers, Analog Electronic Circuits, Electromagnetic Wave Theory, Signals and Systems, Microprocessors, Control Systems.

**GPA:** 3.65/4.00

Student Clubs: IEEE TOBB ETU, Google Developer Students Club

# Kalaba Anatolian High School, Ankara, Turkey Department of Science

I was the captain of the school's basketball team. **GPA:** 93/100

#### **EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE**

# ESEN System Integration, Ankara, Turkey Long Term Intern

24 May 2021 - 06 September 2021

- Did some research about fundamentals of RF and Microwave Systems
- ✓ Gain basic knowledge of RF/Wireless lab equipment such as Network Vector Analyzer, Analog Signal Generator, and Spectrum Analyzer.
- ✓ Used AWR Microwave Office circuit design software for circuit design and testing.

# Konelsis Control Systems, Ankara, Turkey

June 2019 – July 2019

I have completed this internship in Konelsis before starting to university. Being there, I have seen the production field and learned some basic information about my major.

# **PROJECTS**

# Implementation of the Advanced Encryption Standard using Verilog

With a focus on resource utilization efficiency and pipelining, I have assisted the team for implementation of Advanced Encryption Standard using Verilog.

# Designing a Five Staged Power Amplifier and Forming a PCB Layout

Designed a five staged power amplifier with 1000 voltage gain, a bandwidth between 20 Hz - 1 MHz and 2 W RMS power at the load while using common elements like emitter follower, common emitter and Class AB Power Amplifier. In addition, created a PCB layout from the five staged amplifiers schematic using AutoCAD Eagle.

# **SKILLS**

